9873709494;Shruti.dmic@gmail.com; Delhi

PROFILE SUMMARY

Having 7 + years of post-qualification experience in maintenance of Finance and Accounts department. Looking forward to be a part of an organization where process of learning never ends and to be a member of strong professional team committed to excellence and innovation.

ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS

INSTITUTE OF CHARTERED ACCOUNTANTS OF INDIA

EXAM	YEAR	PERCENTAGE
C.A FINAL (Both Groups)	May 2011	52.00
C.A INTER (Both Groups)	Nov 2008	50.00
C.A FOUNDATION	Nov 2006	75.00

ACADEMIC QUALIFICATION

EXAM	UNIVERSITY	YEAR	PERCENTAGE
B.COM. (Hons.)	University Of Delhi	2009	69.17
XII	CBSE	2006	86.00
X	CBSE	2004	82.20

KEY SKILLS

- 100 hrs structured training course (ITT) from ICAI.
- Knowledge of MS Excel, MS Word, Powerpoint.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Delhi Mumbai Industrial Corridor Development Corporation Limited, New Delhi

Designation: Manager (Finance & Accounts)

01.04.2018 to till date

- Finalisation of Annual Accounts standalone as well as consolidated accounts.
- Computation of Taxable Income & filing of E-Returns.
- E-TDS Filing and Checking of TDS deduction & deposit of the same.
- Timely deposit of service tax and filing of service tax return.
- Filing of returns GST returns and payment of taxes.
- Responding to the notices received from the Income Tax Department.
- Preparation of Annual Budget and MIS report.
- Management of relationship with client by active interaction for requirements and sorting of accounting problems faced on need basis.
- Computation and processing of staff salary.
- Working with Tally and BUSY.
- Reply to RTI Queries.
- Planning and organizing statutory and internal audit efficiently and preparing audit plans at different stages and ensuring timely completion of audit.
- Assisting CAG auditors during the audit and preparing the replies to their observations.

Delhi Mumbai Industrial Corridor Development Corporation Limited, New Delhi Designation: Assistant Manager Manager (Finance) 01.04.2016 to 31.03.2018

- Finalisation of Annual Accounts standalone as well as consolidated accounts.
- Computation of Taxable Income & filing of E-Returns.
- E-TDS Filing and Checking of TDS deduction & deposit of the same.
- Timely deposit of service tax and filing of service tax return.
- Filing of returns GST returns and payment of taxes.
- Computation and processing of staff salary.
- Working with Tally and BUSY.
- Planning and organizing statutory and internal audit efficiently and preparing audit plans at different stages and ensuring timely completion of audit.

Delhi Mumbai Industrial Corridor Development Corporation Limited, New Delhi Designation: Finance Executive 03.03.2014 to 31.03.2016

- Finalisation of Annual Accounts standalone as well as consolidated accounts.
- Computation of Taxable Income & filing of E-Returns.
- E-TDS Filing and Checking of TDS deduction & deposit of the same.
- Timely deposit of service tax and filing of service tax return.
- Filing of returns GST returns and payment of taxes.
- Computation and processing of staff salary.
- Working with Tally and BUSY.
- Planning and organizing statutory and internal audit efficiently and preparing audit plans at different stages and ensuring timely completion of audit.

National Meat and Poultry Processing Board – Ministry of food Processing Industries Designation: Accounts Officer 01.04.2013 to 03.03.2014

- Preparation of Annual Budget
- Preparation of MIS reports
- Compliance with the observation of the auditors
- Processing of bills
- Processing of staff salary
- Finalization of Accounts
- Computation of taxable income and filing of return
- Timely deposition of TDS and service tax
- Filing of TDS return and service tax return
- Accounting entries in Tally
- Working on EFC and SFC notes

National Meat and Poultry Processing Board – Ministry of food Processing Industries Designation: Accounts Assistant 08.05.2012 to 31.03.2013

- Processing of staff salary
- Finalization of Accounts

- Computation of taxable income and filing of return
- Timely deposition of TDS and service tax
- Filing of TDS return and service tax return
- Accounting entries in Tally
- Processing of bills

M/S Shyam Goel & Associates, Chartered Accountants

Designation: Audit Assistant 01.10.2010 to 30.04.2012

- Preparation of audit plans
- Assisting in internal and statutory audits
- Drafting of notes to accounts
- Verification of transactions and balance for expression of opinion
- Computation of taxable income
- Filing of e-returns
- Accounting entries in Busy and Tally
- Preparation of replies to the notices received from income tax department

M/S Shyam Goel & Associates, Chartered Accountants

Designation: Article Assistant 18.12.2006 to 17.06.2010

- Assisting in internal and statutory audits
- Drafting of notes to accounts
- Verification of transactions and balance for expression of opinion
- Computation of taxable income
- Filing of e-returns

HOBBIES

- Playing badminton
- Listening music

PERSONAL DATA

Father Name - Shri J.L. Gupta
Date of birth - 19 September 1988
Languages known - Hindi, English

Nationality - Indian

Declaration: - I hereby declare that all the above information given is correct to the best of my knowledge.

Date: 27th May, 2019 **Place:** New Delhi